Finding aid to the Office of the President Thomas Corwin Mendenhall Files. CA.MS.00032
Smith College Archives
- Series XIII. GRADUATE WORK, 1.25 linear feet (3 containers)
  The Graduate Work series includes correspondence, news clippings, and reports regarding the evolution and operation of several graduate studies programs at the college. There are records documenting general aspects of graduate education, as well as specific programs of study, such as the American Studies Diploma Program, teacher training at the Clarke School for the Deaf, the Smith-Northampton Summer School, the Master of Arts in Teaching program; the Department of Theater and Speech's Master of Fine Arts program; and the School of Social Work. There are also records documenting the evolution of continuing education programs for alumnae which led to a Smith graduate degree. Information about other educational programs for alumnae which did not lead to a degree can be found in the Alumnae series.
  - General, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Studies Diploma Program, 1962-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Continuing Education for Alumnae
    - General, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Connecticut, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Washington, D.C., 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Washington, D.C., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Washington, D.C., 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Education & Child Study
    see also Series II. Academic Departments Education & Child Study
    - Clarke School Teacher Training, 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Smith-Northampton Summer School-Annual Reports, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Annual Reports, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - General, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - General, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - School for Social Work-Annual Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - -General, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - -General, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - -General, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - -General, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - -General, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - -Accreditation, 1962-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - -Committee on Governance, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - -Committee on Governance, JAN-FEB 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - -Committee on Governance, MAR-NOV 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - -Male Students, 1961-1964; 1968; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - -Search for Dean, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - -Student Unrest, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Theatre and Speech Department, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    see also Series II. Academic Departments- Theatre and Speech
- Series XIV. INTERCOLLEGIATE ASSOCIATIONS, 2.5 linear feet (6 containers)
  There are four intercollegiate associations included in this series: Five Colleges, Inc., the Seven Sisters, the Twelve-College Exchange, and the College Research Center.
  Five Colleges: The Five Colleges material includes correspondence, reports and news clippings tracing the evolution of cooperative relations between Smith College, Mount Holyoke College, Hampshire College, Amherst College, and the University of Massachusetts at Amherst.
  Seven Sisters: The records of the Seven Sisters include correspondence, reports and news clippings documenting relations between seven of the most important women's colleges in the Eastern United States: Barnard, Bryn Mawr, Mount Holyoke, Radcliffe, Smith, Vassar, and Wellesley.
  Twelve-College Exchange: The Twelve-College Exchange files include records of the student exchange program begun in 1969 which eventually included the following institutions: Smith, Amherst, Bowdoin, Connecticut, Dartmouth, Mount Holyoke, Trinity, Vassar, Wellesley ,Wesleyan, Wheaton, and Williams. The program had a publicly stated purpose of expanding the collegiate experience for the students, but privately was initiated as an experiment in coeducation for several traditionally single-sex institutions.
  College Research Center: The College Research Center began in 1962 as a cooperative research program, focusing specifically on administrative and educational issues at women's colleges. The initiating institutions were Mount Holyoke, Vassar, and Wheaton. Smith College joined the center in its third year, but remained only until 1967. The records in this series include reports and correspondence generated by the center and its participating institutions. Other members of the center during Smith's involvement include: Hollins, Sweet Briar, Briarcliff, Connecticut, Trinity, and Randolph-Macon Woman's Colleges. Brown University was not a member of the center but served as a consultant and a home for the center in the earliest stages.
  - College Research Center, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Five Colleges
    - General, 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General-Coordinator, 1960-1961; 1967; 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General-Meetings, 1959-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Academic Departments & Programs
      - Reports, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Afro-American Studies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Afro-American Studies, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Afro-American Studies, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Afro-American Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Afro-American Studies-Mississippi Summer Project, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Classics, 1956-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Dance, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - English, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - History, 1960; 1967; 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - International Studies, 1961; 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Languages, 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Latin American Studies, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Music, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Non-Western Studies, 1959-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Philosophy, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Science-General, 1959-1964; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Science-Astronomy, 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Science-History of Science, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Science-Instrument Report, 1959; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Academic Policy Advisory Council, 1969; 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Amherst College-Coeducation, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Amherst College-Task Force on Amherst College & Cooperative and Exchange Programs, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Charter Flights, 1959-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Coalition for Aid to Private Higher Education, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Computing Center, 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Credit Union, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Hiring/Exchange, 1959-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Seminars, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Five College Cooperation Study, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Five College Cooperation Study Report, part 1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Five College Cooperation Study Report, part 2, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Studies, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Graduate Studies-MCA Theatre Writing Fellowship, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Housing, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Law Center, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Libraries, 1956; 1960; 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Long-Range Planning Committee, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Manpower Studies Center Proposal, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Mary Holmes Junior College Enrichment Program, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Massachusetts Review, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Museum of Natural History Proposal, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Radio-WFCR, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Radio-WFCR, 1965-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Students-Minorities-Amherst College, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Hampshire College, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Mount Holyoke College, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Puerto Rican Student Federation, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Univ. of Massachusetts, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Students-Unrest, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Students-Unrest-Rockefeller Grant, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Teaching Assistance, Office of, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Television, 1964-1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Transportation System, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Transportation System, 1962-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Valley Center for Cooperative Education, Proposed, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Valley Women's Center/Institute, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Seven Sisters
    - General, 1959-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Conference Minutes and Agendas, 1959-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Conference Planning, 1959-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scholarships and Admissions, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Scholarships and Admissions, 1964-1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Trusts/Funding, 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Twelve-College Exchange, 1968
    - General, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - General, JAN-AUG 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - General, SEP-DEC 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - General, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Series XV. NON-SMITH ORGANIZATIONS, 1.667 linear feet (4 containers)
  The material in this series documents the variety of national, regional and local organizations which had an impact on and a relationship with the college. Included are reports, news clippings and correspondence with a number of academic, civic, corporate and nonprofit organizations. President Mendenhall was particularly active with the College Entrance Examination Board, the Association of American Colleges, and the Association of Independent Schools and Universities of Massachusetts. In 1962 he helped to found Catalyst, a national organization devoted to supporting women returning to the workforce. The files in this series are organized alphabetically by organization, with two files of miscellaneous organizations at the end, also organized alphabetically.
  - American Association of University Professors-General, 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Association of University Professors-Salary Scale Reports, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Association of University Women, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Association of University Women, 1966-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1964; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Council on Education, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Council on Education, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Security Council, 1962; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Association of American Colleges-Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Colleges, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Colleges, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Colleges, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities in Massachusetts, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities in Massachusetts, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Association of Massachusetts Independent Colleges and Universities, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Canadian-American Women's Association, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Catalyst, 1963-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - College Art Association of America, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - College Entrance Examination Board, 1959-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    see also Series V. Admin Offices-Financial Aid-College Entrance Examination Board
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Council for Basic Education, 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Council on Student Travel, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Higher Education Facilities Commission, Commonwealth of Mass., 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Institute for Architecture and Urban Studies, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Institute of International Education, 1960-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Institute for Off Campus Experience, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - International Voluntary Services, Inc., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Commission on Accrediting, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    see also Series XV. Non-Smith Orgs- Association of American Colleges
  - National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Council of Women, 1962; 1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - National Service Secretariat, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges
    - General, 1958-1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Accreditation-Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Accreditation-Evaluation Information, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Accreditation-Evaluation Report, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Northern Educational Services
    See Series V. Administrative Offices- Special Programs-Smith-Amherst Tutorial
  - New England Association of Social Studies Teachers, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New England Board of Higher Education, 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - New England Colleges Fund, 1958; 1963-1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Peace Corps, 1961-1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Planned Parenthood, 1962-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Roper Public Opinion Research Center, 1964; 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - TIAA/CREF, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - United Negro College Fund, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - University Press of Northern New England, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Western Massachusetts Public Interest Research Group, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Women's College Board of Chicago, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - World Affairs Council of the Connecticut Valley, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, A-L, 1959-1975; undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, M-Z, 1959-1975; undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Series XVI. SPEECHES, 2.083 linear feet (5 containers)
  The duties of the President included many public speaking engagements, not only at Smith College events but at local and national gatherings as well. The records in this series include notes and some full texts for many of these speeches. There is also a collection of note cards and clippings of quotes Mendenhall gathered on various topics for use in both his writings and speaking engagements. The records in this series are filed chronologically by event and are labeled with one or all of the following: title, location, and event. More detailed information about the events themselves can be found in the Events and Engagements series, and in some cases in the records of sponsoring Smith Administrative Offices, Academic Departments or Committees & Boards, as well as Non-Smith Organizations.
  - Smith-First Formal Talk as President, DEC 9, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Northampton High School Commencement-"The Great Majority", JUN 19, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Smith Assembly-First Chapel, SEP 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Smith Assembly-On Letter-Writing, OCT 7, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Smith Inaugural, OCT 15, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Smith Service Clubs Dinner-"Town & Gown Northampton Style", OCT 26, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Smith Assembly-"Scholarship", OCT 28, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Smith Arts Council-"The Historian's Craft & the Crafty Historian", NOV 3, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - University of Hartford Cornerstone Laying, NOV 3, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Smith Assembly-International Students' Day, NOV 18, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Smith Assembly-"Confusion and Contradiction about the Purposes of a Liberal Arts Education", DEC 2, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hartford Smith Club"-Some First Impressions of Smith College and Women's Education", DEC 8, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Smith Assembly-On Abolishing Christmas, DEC 9, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Neilson Library Anniversary, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Smith Assembly-"One World or Two", JAN 6, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Smith Assembly, FEB 3, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Smith Alumnae Council Dinner-"The Responsibility of Smith College for the Continuing Education of Women", FEB 16, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Smith Rally Day, FEB 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Club-"Space, Time, and History", FEB 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Smith Assembly-"The Residential Idea at Smith College", MAR 9, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Smith Assembly-"Present Fondness of Criticizing Higher Education", APR 27, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Smith Assembly-Last Chapel, JUN 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Smith Baccalaureate, JUN 5, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Spence School Commencement, JUN 8, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hotchkin School Commencement, JUN 11, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Liberty, Equality and Fraternity in American Independent Education", Spring 1960? (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Smith Alumnae College, Spring 1960? (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Smith Assembly-First Chapel, SEP 27, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Smith Assembly-Introducing the Dean, OCT 5, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Association of Admissions Counselors, Pittsburgh, PA- "College Admissions and After", OCT 10, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Farmington Fund Dinner, Miss Porter's School, Boston, MA, OCT 13, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Smith Assembly-"College Finances in the Year 1960", OCT 26, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - New York City YWCA's 90th Anniversary-"Education & the Emancipated Woman", OCT 27, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Guidance Conference, OCT 1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bryn Mawr School's 75th Anniversary, Baltimore, MD, NOV 4, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Smith Assembly, DEC 14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Smith Assembly-On the New Calendar, FEB 8, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Citizens for the Public Schools Conference, Scarsdale, NY, FEB 18, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Smith Rally Day, FEB 1961 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Smith Alumnae Council, FEB 1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Smith Assembly, MAR 8, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Smith Assembly-Alpha Awards, MAR 22, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1761 Symposium, APR 26, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Smith Assembly-Spofford, Dorius, and Arvin, APR 26, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Colby Junior College Commencement, JUN 4, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Northampton School for Girls Commencement, JUN 5, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Smith Alumnae College, JUN 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Masters School Commencement, JUN 7, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Smith Assembly-Last Chapel, JUN 1961 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Smith Assembly-First Chapel, SEP 18, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Smith Assembly-Introducing the Dean, SEP 26, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Smith Admissions Conference, SEP 1961 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Smith Assembly, SEP 1961 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Smith Assembly, OCT 11, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Smith Assembly-Smith College Presidents, OCT 20, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Wright Hall Dedication, OCT 20, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Smith Assembly-"Interterm Session & Independent Study", NOV 1, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - New Haven, NOV 1961 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Smith Assembly, DEC 6, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - MacDuffie School Dinner-"Equality & Quality in American Education", DEC 13, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Neilson Professorship-Eudora Welty, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Opening of the Interterm, JAN 8, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Smith Assembly, FEB 6, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Smith Assembly-"Conformity, Nonconformity, Education & Independence", FEB 7, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - New York Smith Club, MAR 5, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Smith Assembly, MAR 14, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Tennessee Smith Clubs, MAR 1962 (?) (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Montclair State College-"The Care & Feeding of the Gifted Student", APR 15, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Smith Assembly-Alpha Awards, APR 25, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Hartford College Commencement, JUN 7, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Smith Assembly-Last Chapel, JUN 1962 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Smith Alumnae College, Spring 1962 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Northfield School for Girls Faculty Conference, SEPT 9, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Smith Assembly-First Chapel, SEPT 11, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - School for Social Work Alumnae Meeting, Boston, MA, SEPT 18, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Smith Assembly-Introducing the Dean, SEPT 19, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Smith Assembly, OCT 3, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Association of University Women Meeting-"Continuing Education for Women: Some Informal Thoughts", OCT 6, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Smith Assembly, OCT 17, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Smith's Neilson Library Addition Dedication, OCT 19, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Amherst College Chapel, OCT 25, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Smith Alumnae Council-"The Curriculum in a Liberal Arts College", OCT 30, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Smith Alumnae Council Dinner, OCT 30, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Wilmarth Lewis Introduction, Neilson Library, OCT 31, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Smith Assembly-"Liberal Education & the Educated Woman", NOV 7, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - School for Social Work Alumnae Dinner, New York, NY, NOV 13, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Smith Assembly-International Students Day, NOV 14, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Smith Assembly-Interterm, DEC 5, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chapin School Ethel Gray Stringfellow Lecture, DEC 7, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Smith Admissions Conference, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Smith Assembly, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Washington Smith Club Meeting, JAN 28, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - American Alumni Council, New Haven, JAN 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 50th Anniversary of Mount Herman School Library, Northfield, MA, FEB 1, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Smith Assembly, FEB 6, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Smith Rally Day, FEB 23, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Smith Assembly, MAR 13, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Smith Assembly, MAR 20, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Smith Assembly-S-pins, APR 24, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Smith Assembly-Last Chapel, MAY 31, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Hockaday School Commencement, Dallas, TX-"Different Drummer", JUN 3, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Montclair High School Commencement, JUN 19, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Smith Alumnae College, Spring 1963 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Smith Assembly-First Chapel, SEP 10, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Smith Assembly-Introducing the Dean, SEP 18, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Smith Assembly, SEP 25, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Service Organizations of Smith, OCT 2, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Smith Assembly, OCT 9, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Smith Assembly, OCT 16, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Smith Assembly, OCT 23, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Smith Assembly-International Students Day, NOV 13, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Smith Alumnae College, NOV 14, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Smith Assembly, NOV 20, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Yale Graduate School, NOV 21, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Smith Assembly-Death of John F. Kennedy, NOV 25, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, New York Section-"Excellence or Compromise", JAN 21, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - League of Smith College Clubs of Chicago-"The Future and the Liberal Arts College", JAN 30, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Evanston Smith Club, JAN 1964 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Smith Art Gallery Exhibition, FEB 10, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Smith Rally Day-John Kenneth Galbraith Introduction, FEB 22, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Candidates Conference, FEB 1964 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Smith Assembly, MAR 11, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - New England College Fund Meeting-"School Fund Raisers", MAR 13?, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Smith Phi Beta Kappa Meeting, MAR 18, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Council of Women's College Clubs in Westchester County, NY- "Continuing Education for What?", APR 13, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Smith Assembly-"Manners and Morals in 1964", APR 15, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 54)